A Guide to the Records of the Policy Office: Executive Orders and Memorandum of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, 1986-1993 (bulk 1990-1993)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Policy Office: Executive Orders and Memorandum of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, 1986-1993 (bulk 1990-1993)
The Library of Virginia
35539
1.4 cu. ft. (4 boxes)
Virginia. Governor (1990-1994: Wilder)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder on 31 October 1996.
Scope and Content
Records of the Policy Office: Executive Orders and Memorandum, 1986-1993 (bulk 1990-1993), documenting Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder's directives. Executive Orders are issued by the Governor to accomplish a specific purpose and have the full weight and effect of the law. Executive Memorandums allows the Governor to establish official policy and provide guidance and direction to state agencies without the memorandum having the effect of law. This series consists mostly of copies of executive orders and includes research material involving the topic of the order.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Draft Executive Order, Governor's Economic Advisory Council, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Draft Executive Orders, Emergency Operations Plan, Declarations of States of Emergency, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Executive Orders and Memorandums Instructions, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Executive Orders and Executive Memorandums, Expirations, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Draft Executive Order, Inter-departmental Licensure and Certification of Children Residential Areas, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Reviewed Orders and Memorandums, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Status Report on Executive Documents in Process, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Draft Executive Order, Virginia State Employees Combined Charitable Campaign, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Executive Order # 49 (1987) and Order # 67 (1989), Job Training Partnership Act, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Executive Order # 1, Equal Employment Opportunity, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Executive Order # 2, Project Streamline, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Executive Order # 3, Authority and Responsibility of Chief of Staff, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Executive Order # 4, Withholding General Fund Appropriations, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Executive Order # 5, Reduction of Salaries for State Employees due to Revised General Fund Forecast, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Executive Order # 7, Governor's Commission on Physical Fitness and Sports, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Executive Order # 8, Prohibiting Agencies and Institutions from Investing in Companies with Interest in South Africa, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Executive Order # 9, Assistance of Virginia National Guard and State Police and Emergency Services in Search of Missing Aircraft, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Executive Order # 11, Cooperation between National Guard and State Police in Suppression of Drug Criminal Activity, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Executive Order # 12, Legislative Coordination, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Executive Order # 13, Designation of Executive Branch Officers and Employees Required to File Financial Disclosure Statements, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Executive Order # 14, Governor's Advisory Board of Economist, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Executive Order #15, Continuation of Virginia Coastal Resources Management Program (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Executive Order # 16, Job Training Act, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Executive Orders # 17 (1990) and # 18 (1986), Education Block Grants, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Executive Order # 18, Responsibility of State Officials and Agencies to Participate in the 1980 Super fund Program, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Executive Order # 22, Delegation of Authority, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Executive Order # 23, Review of Regulations Proposed by State Agencies, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Executive Orders # 24, 25, 26, Providing Assistance for Labor Day Weekend in Virginia Beach, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Executive Order # 26, Promulgation of Commonwealth of Virginia Emergency Operations Plan, Closing of the Chesapeake Bridge Tunnel, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Executive Order # 27, Inter-Departmental Regulation of Children's Residential Facilities, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Executive Order W (Authority and Responsibility of the Governor's Secretaries) and Order X (Delegation of Authority for Certain Actions Affecting Management of the Commonwealth), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Draft Executive Orders, Coordination of Services for Veteran's and Families, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Draft Executive Orders, Federal Limit on Tax Credits for Low-Income Housing, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Draft Executive Orders, Creating the Debt Capacity Advisory Committee, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Draft Executive Orders, Virginia War Memorial Foundation and Board of Trustee, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Executive Order A-91, Streamlining Administrative Burdens on Local Governments Related to State Financial Assistance Programs, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Executive Order BB, Declaration of State of Emergency, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Executive Order CC, Declaration State of Emergency Fire in Wakefield, Virginia, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Executive Order # 30, Creation of Task Force on Substance Abuse and Sexual Assault on College Campuses, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Executive Order #31 (DD), Federal Limit on Tax Credits for Low Income Housing, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Executive Order # 33, Delegation of Authority to Secretaries, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Executive Order # 34, States of Emergency Due to Natural Disasters, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Executive Order # 37, Virginia Energy Plan, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Executive Order # 38, Debt Capacity Advisory Committee, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Executive Order # 39, Providing Assistance for Labor Day Weekend, in Virginia Beach, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Executive Order # 40, Federal Limit on Tax Credits for Low Income Housing, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Executive Order# 41, Providing for the Coordination of Executive Branch Agencies in Services Provided to Veterans and their Families, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Proposed Executive Order, Reallocation of Private Activity Board Authority for Housing, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Executive Order # 1, Replacement of Emblem with the Flag of the United States of America, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Executive Order # 43, Creating the Governor's Commission on Defense Conversion and Economic Adjustment, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Executive Order # 44, Virginia National Guard Sent to Kentucky to Fight Forest Fires, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Executive Order # 45, April Flooding Emergency, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Executive Order # 46, Revised Governor's Commission on Campaign Finance Reform Government Accountability and Ethics, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Executive Order # 47, Anti-Crime Partnership Program, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Executive Order # 48, Governor's Commission on Violent Crime, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Executive Order # 49, Governor's Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Executive Order # 50, Governor's Advisory Commission on Worker's Compensation, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Executive Order # 51, Continuing Certain Declarations of States of Emergency Due to Natural Disaster, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Executive Order # 52, Governor's Commission on the Pickett Road Tank Farm, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Executive Order # 53, Centralized Fleet Assignment Criteria to other State-owed Passenger Vehicles, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Executive Order # 54, Delegations on Authority to Officials in Office of Administration, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Executive Order # 55, Governor Authority under Federal Inter modal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Executive Order # 56, Emergency Travel Authorization for Trucks Hauling Goods to Disaster Area, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Executive Order # 57, Hot line for State Employees to Report Fraud, Waste or Abuse (Proposed), 1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Executive Order # 57, Review of Regulations Proposed by State Agencies, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Executive Order # 58, Job Training Partnership Act, (Proposed), 1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Executive Order # 59, Promoting the Commonwealth's Economic Development through VEDCORP Inc. (Proposed), 1992 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Executive Order # 59, Declaration of a State of Emergency Arising from Heavy Snowfall in Frederick County, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Executive Order # 60, Delegation of Authority in General Obligation Bond Acts, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Executive Memorandum # 3, Natural Disaster Due to Pine Bark Beetle Infestation, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Executive Memorandum # 4, Conservation Treatment of State-owned Agricultural Lands, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Executive Memorandum # 5, Stimulating Recycling Markets, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Draft Executive Order, Continuing Governor's Commission on Violent Crime, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Proposed Smoking Ban in Public Buildings, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Proposed Executive Order, Use of Camp Pendleton over Labor Day, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Executive Order # 63, Continuing the Governor's Advisory Commission on Worker's Compensation, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Executive Order # 64, Governor's Advisory Commission on Revitalization of Virginia's Urban Areas, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Executive Order # 66, Cavazos-Draught Act, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Executive Order # 67, Rescind Executive Order 56 Emergency Travel Authorization, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Executive Order # 68, Continuing Governor's Commission on Defense Conversion and Economic Adjustments, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Executive Order # 69, Establishing the Governor's Advisory Commission on Welfare Reform, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Executive Order # 70, Continuing Certain Declarations of States of Emergency Due to Natural Disasters, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Executive Order # 71, Continuing Governor's Commission on Violent Crime, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Executive Order # 72, Declaration of State of Emergency Arising from a Storm System, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Executive Order # 73, Providing for Assistance of the National Guard to the State Police for the Southern Governor's Association/African Head of State Summit, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Executive Order # 74, Job Training Partnership Act Related Programs, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Executive Order # 75, Emergency Travel Authorization for Trucks Hauling Goods to Flood Disasters to Certain Areas, in the Midwest, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Executive Order # 76, Declaration of a State of Emergency Arising from Tornadoes in Parts of Virginia, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Executive Order # 77, Declaration of State of Emergency Arising from a Fire in Chesterfield County, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Executive Order # 77, Declaration of State of Emergency in Chesterfield County, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Executive Order # 78, Declaration of State of Emergency Arising from Imminent Arrival of Hurricane Emily, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Executive Order # 79, Rescinding Executive Order # 8 Concerning Divesture from South African Companies, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Executive Order # 80, Emergency Travel Authorization for Truck Hauling Goods to Drought Stricken Areas in South Carolina, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Executive Order # 81, Establishing the Virginia-Middle East Peace Commission, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Executive Order # 82 Proscribing Those Persons Who Have Received Notices from the Governor Elect George F. Allen to Submit their Resignation from Responding to Such Notice, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 18)